...a report by this entertainment industry analyst released today...
... selon un analyste de l'industrie du spectacle,
showed a severe drop in the summer box office results at the major studios.
il semblerait que les chiffres du box-office soient sérieusement en baisse.
A Warner Brothers spokesperson pooh-poohed the projections....
Chez Warner, on s'inquiète bien peu des prévisions...
Previn?
Previn ?
Previn, are you in there?
Previn, vous êtes là ?
It's George, the building manager.
C'est George, le concierge.
I started to smell something a few days ago...
Je sens une odeur depuis quelques jours,
but I just thought someone was cooking cabbage.
mais j'ai pensé que quelqu'un faisait du chou.
See? You can still smell it. I'm not crazy.
Vous voyez ? L'odeur n'est pas partie. Je ne suis pas folle.
Oh, my God!
Oh, mon Dieu !
I'm just surprised.
Je suis juste surpris.
Why? I told you I was going to write a book.
Je t'avais dit que j'allais écrire un livre.
-No, you didn't. -I thought I did.
- Non. - Je pensais que si.
-What? -I need to get in there.
- Quoi ? - Laisse-moi passer.
So you're just gonna sit down today and start writing?
Donc, tu vas t'asseoir et te mettre à écrire ?
Yeah, I think that's how it's usually done.
Il me semble que c'est comme ça qu'on s'y prend.
Except for Hemingway. He stood.
A part Hemingway qui écrivait debout.
-What? -I need to get in there now.
- Quoi ? - Laisse-moi passer.
-What? You think I can't write a book? -No, of course not.
- Tu penses que je ne peux pas écrire ? - C'est pas ce que je veux dire.
It's just a book is so big.
Mais un livre, c'est long.
Not all of them.
Pas tous.
Well, it's just the last time we talked about you doing something new...
La dernière fois qu'on a parlé de tes projets,
you mentioned getting Billy's friends to help you open an art gallery.
des amis de Billy devaient t'aider à ouvrir une galerie d'art.
Yeah, well, I got to thinking.
J'ai réfléchi.
I don't need to help others express themselves.
Je n'ai pas besoin d'aider les autres à s'exprimer.
I should do it myself.
Je dois m'exprimer, moi.
I think this is great.
Je trouve que c'est super.
Charlotte finally speaks.
Charlotte Brontë s'exprime.
Your fucked-up childhood from your point of view. People will want to read that.
Ton enfance de merde, vue par toi. Ca va intéresser tout le monde.
No way. I'm not gonna write a memoir.
Je ne compte pas écrire mes mémoires.
What is it, then?
Quoi, alors ?
-Fiction. -Really?
- De la fiction. - Ah oui ?
That's so ambitious. I love it.
Très ambitieux. J'adore.
I hope I'm going to be in it. I've always wanted to be thinly veiled.
Je serai dedans, j'espère. On me devinera derrière un des personnages.
You might be in it...
Ca se pourrait.
if you ever do anything interesting.
Le jour où tu feras quelque chose d'intéressant.
I need help.
J'ai besoin d'aide.
Do you think the hair on Mr. Peterson's forearms is sexy?
Tu trouves les bras velus de M. Peterson sexy ?
Or is it too unkempt? Sometimes he gets all tufty.
Ou c'est du laisser-aller ? Parfois, ça fait des touffes.
I really don't have time for this.
Je n'ai pas le temps de parler de ça.
This weekend is my last chance to take the SATs. I have to do well.
Je dois réussir mes examens d'entrée à la fac. C'est ma dernière chance.
Just take a break. It'll keep you from burning out.
Fais une pause. Il ne faut pas t'épuiser.
Every fall, I rate the male teachers' fuckability.
Chaque automne, je donne une note de baisabilité aux profs.
I've been doing it since the sixth grade.
Je fais ça depuis la 6e.
I am, like, 400 times smarter than you.
Je suis, style, 400 fois plus intelligente que toi.
Why aren't you panicking more about this test?
Pourquoi ne paniques-tu pas plus que ça ?
Because I know how to play the game.
Je connais les règles du jeu.
I have a tutor. I've taken practice tests.
J'ai des cours particuliers. J'ai passé des examens blancs.
And my mom's life coach is advising me.
Le coach perso de ma mère me donne des conseils.
Your mom's life coach?
Le coach personnel de ta mère ?
Parker, do you have any idea what a parody of yourself you are?
Parker, as-tu jamais réalisé quelle parodie de toi-même tu fais ?
I feel bad for Mr. Van Kirk.
Je suis embêtée pour M. Van Kirk.
If he hadn't stopped working out, he could've easily cracked the top 10.
S'il n'avait pas arrêté la muscu, il serait dans les 10 premiers.
Give me that.
Donne-moi ça.
Gitterman's coming in at 22?
Gitterman est 22e ?
I was feeling generous.
Je me sentais d'humeur généreuse.
-Hey, Claire. -Gary, hi.
- Salut, Claire. - Gary.
-See you this afternoon? -Yep.
- On se voit cet après-midi ? - Ouais.
Gary has a great ass.
Gary a un super cul.
-You think he has a great ass? -Yeah.
- Tu trouves ? - Ouais.
Like you haven't noticed.
Comme si t'avais pas remarqué.
My mom calls them buns. She's so not of this century.
Ma mère appelle ça un popotin. Comme au siècle dernier.
I don't care how much she pays her life coach.
Je me fiche de savoir combien elle paie son coach.
I could fuck Gary. Easy.
Je me taperais volontiers Gary.
So this woman in her 40s just died alone in her apartment?
Cette femme de 40 ans est donc morte seule dans son appartement ?
Just out of the blue?
Juste comme ça ?
I mean, she must have had some kind of medical condition.
Elle devait sûrement être malade.
No, she choked to death.
Non, elle s'est étouffée.
She lay there for a week before anyone found her.
On ne l'a trouvée qu'au bout d'une semaine.
Why didn't anybody notice sooner?
Pourquoi si longtemps ?
Maybe they thought she was on vacation.
Ils ont dû la croire en vacances.
Here are the arrangements for her funeral. They're self-explanatory.
Voilà les détails de son enterrement. Rien de compliqué.
You should be able to take care of it.
Tu devrais pouvoir t'en occuper.
Shouldn't I talk to whoever's gonna bury her?
Je ne devrais pas en parler à ses proches ?
Nate, it's a pre-need. She buried herself.
Nate, elle s'est occupée de tout avant sa mort.
She bought everything she wanted ahead of time.
Elle a tout payé à l'avance.
You have her contacts for family and friends, directions for the service...
Voilà comment joindre famille et amis, le plan pour la cérémonie,
and the specifications about her restoration.
les requêtes pour l'embaumement.
She knew exactly what kind of service she wanted.
Elle savait exactement ce qu'elle voulait.
You'll need to order the sheet music for the organist.
Il faut commander la partition pour l'organiste.
And I Am Telling You I'm Not Going.
Et je te dis que je ne m'en vais pas.
She certainly had a sense of humor.
Elle avait le sens de l'humour.
What song is that?
Tu connais cette chanson ?
It's from Dreamgirls. You know it:
De la comédie Dreamgirls. Tu sais bien ?
And I am telling you
Et je te dis
I'm not going
Que je ne m'en vais pas
You're the best man I've ever known
Jamais je n'ai rencontré de meilleur homme que toi
It must be weird to fill one of these things out for yourself.
Ca doit être bizarre de remplir un de ces trucs pour soi-même.
I had fun doing mine.
J'ai bien aimé faire le mien.
I have a test on Monday, I have an art history paper due next week.
J'ai un examen lundi et un devoir pour la semaine prochaine.
I know I could do a good job on both if I had more time, but I don't.
Si j'avais plus de temps je pourrais les réussir tous les deux, mais...
-Do I have something on my face? -No.
- J'ai quelque chose sur le nez ? - Non.
You're giving me this look.
Pourquoi me regardez-vous comme ça ?
It's just nice to see you so involved.
J'aime vous voir impliquée.
Are you taking the SAT this weekend?
Vous passez vos examens d'admission cette semaine ?
I saw the books in the library.
J'ai vu les livres à la bibliothèque.
-I don't know why I didn't tell you. -It's okay.
- Je sais, je ne vous l'ai pas dit. - Pas de souci.
-I just signed up for it. I wasn't sure. -No, it's great.
- Je me suis inscrite comme ça. - C'est super.
You're taking school more seriously, and you're gonna take the SAT.
Vous prenez vos études plus au sérieux, et vous allez passer vos examens.
-It shows you're nurturing yourself. -Give me a break.
- Vous prenez soin de vous. - Oh, lâchez-moi.
I'm so scared of having my own thoughts or going my own direction...
J'ai si peur de mes propres pensées, de suivre mon chemin,
that I need some safety or approval.
j'ai besoin de sécurité, d'approbation.
This stuff is just cop-out distractions.
Tout ça, c'est pour éviter de passer à l'action.
You know what? This session's given me some clarity.
Vous savez, j'y vois plus clair, grâce à cette séance.
I should just blow this test off...
Je devrais envoyer valdinguer ces examens,
and look really hard inside myself for what I really want.
et chercher ce que je veux vraiment faire à l'intérieur de moi.
Claire, you're obviously frightened by taking this test. Why?
Claire, il est évident que vous avez peur des examens. Pourquoi ?
I don't know.
Je ne sais pas.
It's like, when I think about the test...
Quand j'y pense,
I see this nasty fluorescent light.
je vois une horrible lumière fluorescente.
The kind that shows all your pockmarks and tiny scars that you wish you could hide.
Le genre qui montre toutes les marques et les cicatrices qu'on veut cacher.
I see.
Je vois.
So it's very safe in the darkness, isn't it?
L'obscurité est plus sécurisante, n'est-ce pas ?
Okay, you're getting kind of corny.
Encore une de vos phrases de psy.
All I'm saying is you're finally in a place where you're coming into your own.
Le moment est venu de montrer qui vous êtes réellement,
You're afraid if people see the real you, it'll be scary. And guess what? It is scary.
et qu'on vous trouve effrayante. Il y a de quoi avoir peur.
For all of us. Isn't it?
On a tous peur de ça.
Don't be silly, David.
Ne sois pas bête, David.
You don't need to apologize for what you said about The Plan.
Tu n'as pas besoin de t'excuser de ce que tu as dit.
If you live in a neighborhood for a long time...
Quand on vit dans un quartier depuis longtemps,
and somebody moves in and renovates the house across the street...
qu'un nouveau propriétaire rénove la maison en face,
that could just make you feel your own house is shabby.
on a l'impression que sa maison est miteuse.
I see.
Je vois.
-Did you just insult me? -Of course not.
- C'était une insulte ? - Certainement pas.
You'll see.
Tu verras.
When you're ready, you're going to live in a palace.
Quand le moment sera venu, tu vivras dans un palace.
Claire, wash your hands. We're about to eat.
Claire, lave-toi les mains. A table.
Don't set a place for me. I'm not staying.
Ne mets pas mon couvert. Je sors.
-Who are you having dinner with? -No one.
- Avec qui dînes-tu ? - Personne.
I'm having coffee with someone I met at St. Stephen's.
Je vais prendre un café avec quelqu'un de St Stephen.
David, if you have a date, just say it.
David, si tu as un rendez-vous, tu peux nous le dire.
Nothing ever gets built if the materials aren't labeled properly.
On ne construit rien sans étiqueter les matériaux correctement.
Okay, I have a date.
J'ai un rendez-vous.
David, I'm having a problem with the Emily Previn funeral.
David, j'ai un problème avec l'enterrement d'Emily Previn.
Let's hear it.
Dis-moi.
I've called her entire contact list, and the friends she listed have moved or died.
J'ai appelé tous les gens sur sa liste, ses amis sont morts, ou ont déménagé.
She has two distant relatives.
Elle a deux cousins éloignés.
One of which I can't reach, and the other has this phobia about funerals.
Un que je n'arrive pas à joindre, l'autre a une phobie des funérailles.
Some people are so sick.
Il y a vraiment des malades.
Now we know why she wasn't found for a week.
Maintenant, on sait pourquoi on ne l'a pas trouvée plus vite.
-I don't think she had anybody in her life. -How awful.
- Je crois qu'elle n'a personne dans la vie. - C'est affreux.
Have you called her job to notify her colleagues about the service?
Tu as appelé à son travail, pour prévenir ses collègues ?
No. She worked at a temp agency, so she just had jobs here and there.
Non, elle travaillait de temps à autre pour une boîte d'intérim.
She must have had someone that she forgot to list.
Elle a sûrement oublié quelqu'un.
Try her high school. Everyone has friends from high school.
Essaie son lycée. Tout le monde garde des amis de lycée.
No, they don't.
Non.
Maybe they have people they talk to, or do things with...
Certaines personnes ont de vagues connaissances,
but they're not really friends.
mais pas de vrais amis.
They're just filler.
Juste de quoi remplir le vide.
What? It's true.
Quoi ? C'est vrai.
I want a glass of wine.
Je veux un verre de vin.
Oh, God.
Seigneur.
It's so weird.
C'est si bizarre.
Who the hell was Emily Previn?
Qui était Emily Previn ?
Nate, are you okay?
Nate, tu vas bien ?
-Yeah, I'm fine. -'Cause your eyes look really weird.
- Oui, très bien. - Tes yeux sont bizarres.
Yeah, it's just this medication I'm taking. It makes me a little drowsy. That's all.
C'est ce médicament, il me rend somnolent, c'est tout.
Honestly.
Je te jure.
Maybe Emily Previn was autistic.
Emily Previn était peut-être une autiste.
I read an article about a high-functioning autistic person who didn't need people.
J'ai lu un article sur une autiste surdouée qui n'avait besoin de personne.
She just had a job designing these big cattle slaughterhouses.
Son boulot, c'était de concevoir des abattoirs.
At night, she came home and sat in a machine...
Le soir, elle rentrait s'asseoir dans une machine
that made her feel like she was being hugged.
qui lui donnait l'impression d'être câlinée.
And that was all the intimacy she needed.
Elle n'avait pas besoin d'autre intimité.
That's really upsetting.
C'est vraiment troublant.
I don't see why this person has to be mentally ill...
Pourquoi il faudrait que ça soit une malade mentale,
just because she had a life that doesn't conform to a familiar image in our heads.
parce que sa vie ne se conformait pas à un schéma familier.
Maybe she was living the life she wanted.
Peut-être avait-elle choisi de vivre comme ça.
A life without the hassle of other people.
Une vie sans se soucier d'autres personnes.
What kind of a life is that?
A quoi ça ressemble, une vie comme ça ?
"Well, I'm sorry, Your Honor...
"Je suis désolé, Votre Honneur,
"but how was I supposed to know it was your car?"
"comment aurais-je su qu'il s'agissait de votre voiture ?"
-I don't think I could be a public defender. -No? Why not?
- Je ne serai jamais avocat commis d'office. - Pourquoi pas ?
I just don't think I could defend people who are guilty.
Je ne pourrais pas défendre des coupables.
I guess I could be a some-of-the-public defender.
Je ne pourrais défendre que certains clients.
So, what do you do?
Que fais-tu ?
Me? My family owns a business. Actually, it's a funeral home.
Moi ? Ma famille a une entreprise de pompes funèbres.
But I got out of that really quickly, and now I'm in textiles.
Mais j'en suis sorti pour entrer dans les textiles.
I like fabric.
J'aime les tissus.
I have to be in court in the morning. I have a lot of work...
Il faut que je sois à la cour demain. J'ai beaucoup de travail...
-Okay. Maybe we'll see each other around. -David, relax.
- Très bien, on se reverra peut-être. - David, calme-toi.
It's fine. I understand. I guess there's not much of a spark here.
Tout va bien. Je comprends. Il n'y a pas d'étincelle entre nous.
I thought there was. You don't?
Je croyais que si, pas toi ?
No, I do. I was just worried.
Si, si, mais j'étais inquiet.
I'm sorry, Ben. I get a little nervous at these things.
Désolé, Ben. Il m'arrive d'être nerveux.
If I seem calm, it's only because I take a beta-blocker...
Si je semble calme, c'est que je prends un tranquillisant
before I have to get in front of a jury or first dates.
avant d'apparaître devant un jury, ou pour un premier rendez-vous.
You're still nervous on the inside, but you don't show it as much.
Ca n'enlève pas la nervosité, mais ça se voit moins.
Do you have any extra?
Tu en as pour moi ?
Let's go on a real date next time. Like, for dinner.
Et si on se voyait pour dîner, la prochaine fois ?
Okay, that would be nice.
Ca serait sympa.
You seem a little....
Tu as l'air un peu...
-Are you coming out of a bad breakup? -No, I'm coming out of a bad celibacy.
- Tu ne sortirais pas d'une rupture difficile ? - Non, d'un célibat difficile.
I was in a relationship, but that ended.
J'étais en couple, mais c'est terminé.
Well, whatever happened, I blame him.
C'est forcément sa faute à lui.
You shouldn't. He's a great guy.
Non, il est vraiment super.
You get your spoiled little ass into that bed right now! Do you hear me?
Tu vas monter te coucher tout de suite, sale gamine gâtée, tu m'entends ?
You suck!
Tu crains !
Right now! I mean it!
Tout de suite ! Je ne plaisante pas.
I'm not tired.
J'ai pas sommeil.
When I'm at my real home, I don't have to go to sleep until I get tired.
Dans ma vraie maison, je ne me couche pas avant d'être fatiguée.
I'm going to turn off the lights now, and soon you'll be tired.
Je vais éteindre la lumière, et tu auras bientôt sommeil.
What if I never get tired?
Et si ça n'arrivait pas ?
Then you'll lay awake for hours and hours, wondering why life is so hard.
Tu resterais éveillée des heures en te demandant pourquoi ta vie est si dure.
That's what the rest of us do.
Tout le monde fait ça.
That sounds boring.
Ca n'a pas l'air rigolo.
You get used to it.
On s'habitue.
Do you want to talk about anything?
Tu veux me parler de quelque chose ?
Like how you feel about staying here?
Par exemple me dire si ça te plaît d'être ici ?
Or being scared, because your mom's been in Oakland so long?
Si tu as peur parce que ta maman est partie depuis longtemps ?
No.
Non.
Okay. But we don't know how long you're gonna be here.
Très bien. Mais on ne sait pas pour combien de temps tu es là.
So why don't we both try and ease up on each other a little bit, okay?
Il faut qu'on essaie d'être plus cool l'un avec l'autre, d'accord ?
You guys have bad toothpaste.
Il a mauvais goût, votre dentifrice.
My first instinct is to get angry with her. I open my mouth, I hear my father.
Je me mets tout de suite en colère avec elle. C'est comme si c'était mon père qui parlait.
Stop being so hard on yourself. That child is not easy.
Ne sois pas si dur avec toi-même. C'est une enfant difficile.
I swore to myself I would never be like him.
Je me suis juré de ne pas lui ressembler.
I'm not in the mood.
Je ne suis pas d'humeur.
Fine.
Très bien.
Get up!
Lève-toi !
-Hello? -Hi, Melissa. It's Brenda.
- Allô ? - Melissa, c'est Brenda.
Chenowith.
Chenowith.
Your massage therapist.
La masseuse.
Hey, how's it going?
Oh, comment ça va ?
Listen, I was just wondering if you hadn't eaten yet...
Je me demandais si vous aviez déjà déjeuné.
if you wanted to have lunch.
Si on pouvait déjeuner ensemble.
Actually, I'm at a restaurant right now.
Je vous appelle d'un restaurant.
Look, I'm probably breaking all these client/masseuse boundaries.
Je brise sûrement les règles de comportement entre masseuse et cliente.
I'll see you at your regular appointment tomorrow.
On se verra pour votre rendez-vous de demain.
No, I was just gonna say I'm by myself. I'd love the company.
Je me disais justement que j'aimerais avoir de la compagnie.
Thank God.
Dieu merci.
Oh, Jesus!
Seigneur !
This one's gonna be one hell of a ride.
C'est vraiment un cas hyper difficile.
I'm sure you'll be able to take care of it.
Je suis sûr que tu sauras comment t'y prendre.
Yeah? Well, don't be.
Pas si sûr.
She must've been laying out for a week in a partially-ventilated space.
Elle est restée une semaine dans un local peu ventilé.
Why can't everyone die in an air-conditioned room?
Pourquoi meurent-il sans air conditionné ?
Her face is discolored from being lain on.
Son visage a perdu ses couleurs.
That I can fix, although it's gonna take me hours.
Je peux arranger ça, mais ça va me prendre des heures.
Her abdomen's all distended. This woman's got a lot of gas in there.
Son abdomen est distendu. Il y a beaucoup de gaz.
When I poke a hole, we're gonna get some major fumes.
Ca va fumer quand je ferai des trous.
Whew, Nellie!
Bonjour l'ambiance !
I have no idea why I came in here.
Je ne sais même pas ce que je fais là.
-Maybe you have Alzheimer's. -Yeah, maybe.
- C'est l'Alzheimer. - Peut-être.
We really are just biology, aren't we?
On n'est qu'un amas de cellules.
You may need to talk the family out of an open casket.
Il faut convaincre la famille de la mettre dans un cercueil fermé.
-There's only so much I can do, man. -She doesn't have any family.
- Je n'ai pas de baguette magique. - Il n'y aura pas de famille.
-No one? -No friends, or anybody.
- Personne ? - Pas d'amis non plus.
I ran an obituary in the paper today.
J'ai fait paraître un avis de décès aujourd'hui.
I'm just praying someone will read it and come tomorrow.
Je prie que quelqu'un le lise et vienne demain.
Pre-need?
Elle avait payé d'avance ?
If she wanted an open casket, we'll try to give her one.
Si elle veut un cercueil ouvert, on essaiera de faire au mieux.
I'll boost up the fluids and see if that'll bring the swelling down.
Je vais augmenter les fluides, on verra si ça la fait dégonfler.
There's a good chance we're going to get some skin slippage, and then we're screwed.
Mais la peau risque de lâcher, et là, on sera dans la merde.
Maybe she was just some vicious asshole, you know?
Peut-être que c'était une sale vicieuse.
Just twisted and evil. Maybe that's why she didn't have any people in her life.
Tordue et malfaisante. C'est peut-être pour ça qu'elle était si seule.
No.
Non.
You can tell what kind of life people lived even when they're dead.
Ca se voit même quand ils sont morts, ce genre-là.
Yeah, she was all right.
Je suis sûr que c'était quelqu'un de bien.
Please have your IDs out and ready so we can speed things along.
Préparez vos papiers pour ne pas perdre de temps.
-Claire Fisher. -ID?
- Claire Fisher. - Carte d'identité ?
-Sign right here. -Name?
- Signez-ici. - Nom ?
-Parker McKenna. -Let's see.
- Parker McKenna. - Voyons.
Parker. Sign here, please.
Parker. Signez ici.
Next?
Au suivant.
Does anybody have an extra number two pencil?
Qui a un crayon n°2 en trop ?
Here you go.
Tiens.
So it sounds like a pretty serious relationship for you.
Tu as l'air de le prendre au sérieux.
It is.
Oui.
I love Nate. I really do.
J'aime Nate. Vraiment.
But, lately, I feel kind of separate from him.
Mais je m'éloigne de lui en ce moment.
Which I know is healthy on one level.
Ce qui est sain sur un certain plan.
But, on another, I kind of miss how it was.
Mais je regrette que ça ait changé.
When we started seeing each other and weren't together...
Comme au début, quand on était pas ensemble,
I'd be wondering, "What is he doing?" all day long.
je me demandais : "Que fait-il ?", toute la journée.
Now?
Et maintenant ?
I never even think about it.
Je n'y pense plus jamais.
I don't know exactly when it changed.
Je ne sais pas quand ça a changé.
But at some point, he became less present with me.
Mais à un moment, il est devenu moins présent.
Sometimes I think it's because I don't give him enough to be present for.
Il m'arrive de penser que je ne lui offre pas assez pour qu'il veuille être présent.
But then I think, maybe he's not present because he knows if he was really present...
Et puis je me dis, il s'éloigne parce qu'il sait que s'il était plus présent,
then I'd leave him.
je le quitterais.
You know, it's just so sad that you can love somebody so much...
Tu sais, c'est triste de penser qu'on peut aimer quelqu'un très fort,
and have absolutely no idea what's going on in their head.
et n'avoir aucune idée de ce qu'il a en tête.
-Relationships are fucked. -That's what I always say.
- Les relations, c'est baisé d'avance. - C'est ce que je dis toujours.
I haven't had a real relationship in over a decade.
Ca fait plus de 10 ans que je n'ai plus d'histoires de couple.
-Is that because you.... -Because I blow guys for money?
- C'est parce que tu... - Je les suce pour leur fric ?
I'm so sorry. That was....
Désolée. Je...
It's okay.
Pas de problème.
I've only been doing that for about five years.
Je ne fais ça que depuis 5 ans.
So why, then?
Pourquoi, alors ?
I'm just not built for it. Some people aren't, I think.
Je ne suis pas faite pour ça.
It's not healthy or unhealthy. It just is.
Ca n'est ni sain, ni malsain. C'est comme ça.
Oh, shit.
Et merde.
I'm being paged by a client.
C'est un client qui me bippe.
I am not driving out to Calabasas in this traffic.
Je ne vais pas à Calabasas avec les embouteillages.
Let the jerk whack off.
Il n'a qu'à se branler.
You know, I'm really glad you could have lunch.
Je suis contente qu'on ait pu se voir.
Me, too.
Moi aussi.
You know, it means a lot to me that you're so normal around me.
J'apprécie que tu te comportes naturellement avec moi.
Most people have preconceived notions about what I do.
Les gens ont tellement d'a priori.
Yeah, well, people can be such judgmental assholes.
Il y a tellement de trouducs moralisateurs.
You don't have to tell me that.
Je le sais bien.
You want to know what's worse?
Tu veux savoir le pire ?
Most girls want to be my friend so that they can pump me...
Les filles veulent être amies avec moi pour me faire raconter
for all the gory details about being a lady of the evening.
tous les détails scabreux de la vie de prostituée.
It's just question after question, like I'm some kind of freak.
C'est question sur question, comme si j'étais un monstre.
-All right, you get three questions. -Oh, goody!
- Très bien, tu as droit à 3 questions. - Super !
There's that one.
Il y a ça.
No, I think that one makes you look fat.
Non, ça te grossit.
Very funny.
Très drôle.
Which one do you think will look better on Miss Previn?
Mais pour Mlle Previn ?
The pink one.
La rose.
Didn't she specify which gown she wanted, or did Dad slip up?
Elle a précisé ce qu'elle voulait ou papa a oublié de nous le dire ?
No, Dad didn't slip up. She wanted to be buried in her own clothes.
Non, elle voulait qu'on l'enterre dans ses vêtements à elle.
-The outfit she came in with was shot. -Give her the blue to get rid of it.
- Les siens sont fichus. - Prends la bleue pour t'en débarrasser.
It's coming apart in the back.
On dirait une camisole.
David!
David !
-Mom, did you want something? -I was dusting your casket wall.
- Maman, tu veux quelque chose ? - J'époussetais les cercueils.
If this woman wanted to be buried in her own clothes...
Si cette femme veut ses propres vêtements,
then one of you boys should go to her home and pick something out.
allez chez elle lui prendre quelque chose.
Isn't that a bit much?
Tu crois pas que c'est exagéré ?
I remember Dad doing it once or twice. You get the building manager to let you in.
Papa l'a fait une ou deux fois. Le concierge te laissera entrer.
Fine. I'll pick out something dressy.
Je vais prendre quelque chose d'habillé.
Considering the shape her body's in...
Vu l'état où est le corps,
I should pick whatever covers her up the most.
le plus couvrant sera le mieux.
I'll come with you.
Je viens avec toi.
-You don't have to do that. -I know that.
- Ce n'est pas la peine. - Je le sais.
Aren't the guys scary? It must get dangerous.
Tu n'as pas peur ? Ce n'est pas dangereux ?
To tell you the truth, it doesn't.
A vrai dire, pas vraiment.
You just have to trust your instinct. It's never wrong.
Il faut suivre son intuition. Je ne me trompe jamais.
We're kind of like animals that way.
C'est notre partie animale.
When I first meet a client, I take a good long look into his eyes.
Quand je rencontre un client, je le regarde un bon moment.
That stupid stuff they say about looking in people's eyes is true.
C'est vrai, les conneries qu'on entend sur les yeux des gens.
-You just look into them, and you know. -Know what?
- On les regarde, et on sait. - On sait quoi ?
You know, whether someone is right, or whether they're...
S'il sont bien, ou s'ils...
you know, wrong.
ne sont pas bien.
And if they're wrong, you just get out of there immediately.
Dans ce cas, il faut se tirer au plus vite.
No. I think everyone has the answers to everything in life.
On a tous en nous les réponses à tout.
-It's a matter of knowing how to listen. -You're fantastic!
- C'est une question d'écoute. - Tu es fabuleuse.
Fuck, you are!
C'est vrai, merde !
There is no bullshit with you! You are just who you are. Period.
Tu racontes pas de conneries, tu es qui tu es, point final.
Even the way you talk about your work.
Même la façon dont tu parles de ton boulot.
You provide a service for which you're well-compensated.
Tu fournis un service pour lequel tu es bien payée.
-Unlike the rest of us losers. -Please.
- Pas comme nous autres losers. - Je t'en prie.
If there was anything else that paid this much, I would do it in a heartbeat.
Je changerais tout de suite si un autre boulot me rapportait autant.
But there's not a touch of victimhood about you.
Il n'y a pas le moindre soupçon de victime en toi.
It's almost like it's empowering, in a way.
Comme si ça te donnait du pouvoir, en fait.
I went through that whole feminist rationalization stuff at first.
Je suis passée par toute cette rationalisation féministe au début.
Now I'm just a little more honest.
Je suis un peu plus honnête maintenant.
It's just a way to pay the bills.
C'est pour payer mes factures.
Sorry I can't make it to the funeral.
Je ne peux pas venir à l'enterrement, navré.
My kid's got a soccer game.
Mon gosse a un match de foot.
She was one of your tenants, for God's sake.
C'était votre locataire !
She lived among you.
Elle vivait ici.
Hey, come on. I just started, all right?
Je viens de commencer, d'accord ?
She only lived among me for a week.
Ca faisait une semaine qu'on se connaissait.
She never even got to finish her crossword puzzle.
Elle n'avait même pas fini ses mots croisés.
All right, look.
Très bien, écoutez.
-Five minutes? -Yep. Great.
- Cinq minutes ? - Ca marche.
Mom!
Maman !
Eddie needs to adapt to how things have changed.
Eddie doit s'adapter au changement.
I have a lot more responsibility now.
J'ai plus de responsabilités maintenant.
He needs to be more understanding that sometimes I'm gonna be tired, man.
Il doit comprendre que je suis plus souvent fatigué.
-Yeah, kids come first. Period. -Exactly.
- Les gosses d'abord. Point final. - C'est sûr.
Have you had this conversation with him?
Tu en as parlé avec lui ?
He'd just say I need to make more time for him, which would piss me off.
Il dirait que je devrais passer plus de temps avec lui, et ça me gonflerait.
So why bother talking to him about it?
Pourquoi lui en parler ?
Because you keep everything bottled up inside you, my friend.
Parce que tu gardes toujours tout pour toi.
That's not good. That creates cancer.
C'est comme ça qu'on se fait des cancers.
-Give me a break. -It does.
- Lâche-moi. - C'est vrai.
My wife's cousin was a very angry person, but she never showed it.
Ma cousine était toujours en colère, mais ne le montrait jamais.
She just cleaned all day, then she lost both her breasts.
Elle faisait le ménage. Et puis elle a perdu ses deux seins.
It's weird.
C'est bizarre.
You get away from me, dickless fuck!
Tu me touches pas, enculé de mes deux !
-You don't own me. -What the fuck's wrong with you?
- Je ne t'appartiens pas. - Tu es malade ou quoi ?
You know, you fucking lie to me, bitch!
Tu m'as menti, putain de salope !
Bitch, I'll blow your fucking brains out, you stupid cunt!
Salope, je vais te faire sauter le caisson, espèce de putain !
I wish you would, but you don't got the balls to shoot me!
Bonne idée, mais t'as pas assez de couilles pour ça !
-Police! Drop the gun! -Stay out of this! Fucking cops!
- Police ! Lâchez cette arme ! - Tirez-vous ! Putain de flics !
Drop the gun.
Lâchez cette arme.
You shoot me, they'll shoot you. Then you'll be dead!
Si tu me butes, ils te butent. Et t'es un homme mort.
You know what? The world will be a better place!
Et tu sais quoi ? Le monde s'en portera mieux.
-Shut up! -Drop the gun now!
- Ferme-la ! - Lâchez cette arme !
What is wrong with you? What did you do that for?
Tu es malade ou quoi ? Pourquoi tu as fait ça ?
What's wrong with you?
C'est quoi ton problème ?
I like all of these, but they seem so flat.
Elles sont toutes bien, mais un peu ternes.
I wish one had a little more oomph.
Elles ne sont pas assez gaies.
-Just grab that one. That one has oomph. -No, it doesn't.
- Prends celle-ci. Elle est plus sexy. - Non.
Don't rush me, Nate. I'm not nearly done...
Ne me presse pas, Nate. Je n'ai pas fini,
and I haven't even started with the shoes and the jewelry.
et il reste les chaussures et les bijoux.
Nate Fisher.
Nate Fisher.
Yeah, hi. I left a message there for Father Martin Farrell.
Salut. J'ai laissé un message pour le père Martin Farrell.
He was requested by the deceased to officiate at her funeral.
La décédée veut qu'il officie à la cérémonie.
Great! Well, I'm fucked.
Super, je suis dans la merde.
I'm sorry, Sister.
Excusez-moi, ma soeur.
Are there any other priests you'd recommend for a funeral tomorrow?
Pourriez-vous me recommander un prêtre pour un enterrement demain ?
Mom?
Maman ?
-What, are you hungry? -Of course not.
- Tu as faim ? - Non, bien sûr.
-Then, are you ready to go? -I don't know.
- Tu es prête à partir ? - Je ne sais pas.
Maybe she liked solitude.
Elle aimait peut-être la solitude.
Maybe she was living the life she wanted and was happy.
Elle était peut-être heureuse de vivre comme ça.
I hope so.
J'espère que tu as raison.
But what if some nights, she wanted to talk to someone...
Mais si elle voulait parler à quelqu'un au milieu de la nuit,
and she picked up the phone...
qu'elle prenait le téléphone,
and realized she didn't have anyone she could call? What then?
et réalisait qu'elle n'avait personne à appeler ?
We don't know that she didn't have anyone to call. Maybe there was someone.
On n'en sait rien. Elle avait peut-être quelqu'un à appeler.
I hope so.
J'espère que tu as raison.
No one thinks you did anything wrong. You were just doing your job, okay?
On ne vous accuse de rien. On fait notre boulot, d'accord ?
Now I know what's different.
Je sais ce qui a changé.
You're not wearing your glasses tonight.
Tu ne portes pas tes lunettes.
I was getting dressed, and nothing looked right...
Je m'habillais, et rien n'allait comme il fallait,
and I realized it was all my glasses' fault.
et j'ai compris que c'était mes lunettes.
So I put in these contacts, which I actually hate...
J'ai mis mes lentilles, alors que je déteste ça,
but I thought it was worth it, if you'd....
mais ça valait le coup, si tu...
This is me without beta-blockers.
Ca, c'est moi sans tranquillisants.
It's good.
C'est bien.
Maybe it's even better.
Peut-être encore mieux.
-I still work in the family business. -Excuse me?
- Je travaille toujours pour ma famille. - Pardon ?
I'm a funeral director, that's who I am.
Je dirige des pompes funèbres.
I have to say, I'm glad you're not in textiles. That sounded really dull.
Je préfère ça au textile, ça, c'est ennuyeux.
Why did you lie?
Pourquoi mentir ?
Well, come on.
Sans déconner ?
People always get that look in their eyes, like there's something wrong with you.
On me regarde toujours comme si j'étais taré.
They wait about 5 seconds before bringing the conversation around to necrophilia.
Il leur faut pas plus de 5 secondes pour parler de nécrophilie.
I just liked you too much, and I was scared it would repulse you.
Tu me plaisais vraiment, je n'ai pas voulu te faire horreur.
So what made you tell me now?
Pourquoi maintenant ?
Because on our last date, I just sort of liked you...
Parce que la dernière fois, je t'ai assez apprécié,
and now I really like you.
et maintenant je t'apprécie vraiment.
-So I didn't screw things up because I lied? -No, I think it's cute.
- Je n'ai pas tout gâché ? - Non, c'est mignon.
-And I'm gonna wanna take this slow. -All right.
- Je ne veux pas me presser. - Très bien.
Can we just make out, already?
Et si tu commençais par m'embrasser ?
We had plans to meet tonight. At the Tiki Ti.
On devait se voir ce soir. Au Tiki Ti.
Did we?
Ah bon ?
Claire, why did you blow me off? And why didn't you return my phone calls?
Claire, pourquoi ce lapin ? Tu ne me rappelles plus...
Because I have nothing to say to you.
Je n'ai rien à te dire.
Look, I know this is about the SATs, but it wasn't my fault.
Ce n'est pas ma faute, pour les examens.
It was my mother's idea. She heard about this girl through one of her friends.
C'était l'idée de ma mère. Elle a entendu parler de cette fille par une amie.
She's this genius from Westlake who's going around taking the test.
C'est une tête de Westlake qui passe l'examen pour les autres.
And let me tell you, it works.
Et ça marche.
She got three people into Yale and five into Harvard.
Elle en a fait entrer 3 à Yale, et 5 à Harvard.
-This is so gross. -What was I supposed to do?
- C'est ignoble. - Qu'est-ce que je devais faire ?
My mom came into my room last night and told me she'd already paid the girl $1,000.
Ma mère m'a annoncé hier qu'elle l'avait payée 1 000 $.
You make me so sick. Just get out of here!
Tu me dégoûtes. Tire-toi !
Okay? I don't feel like ever seeing you again.
Je ne veux plus jamais te voir.
-You're serious? -Yeah, I am.
- Tu es sérieuse ? - Oui.
Fine. Fuck you, Claire!
Très bien. Va te faire foutre !
By the way, I flirted for 45 minutes with Gary Deitman outside of school yesterday...
Au fait, j'ai flirté avec Gary Deitman devant l'école hier,
and he's this total horny little freak.
il bande comme un cheval.
And I'm gonna bag him, big time.
Et je vais me le faire.
Congratulations. I hope you and his stupid buns will be very happy together!
Félicitations. Sois très heureuse avec ton popotin.
"David Fisher and Benjamin Cooper invite you to a holiday open house. "
"David Fisher et Benjamin Cooper vous invitent à leur journée 'portes ouvertes'."
"Merry Christmas from Ben and David. "
"Joyeux Noël ! Ben et David."
"Happy Holidays from the Cooper-Fishers. "
"Joyeuses fêtes de la part des Cooper-Fisher."
"Fish & Coop, new this fall on ABC. "
"Fish & Coop, dès la rentrée sur votre chaîne ABC."
Keith, what's wrong?
Keith, qu'est-ce qui ne va pas ?
I'm not sure.
Je n'en suis pas sûr.
Okay. Come in and sit down.
Viens, assieds-toi.
I shouldn't have even come here.
Je n'aurais pas dû venir.
It's fine.
C'est bon.
You want a beer?
Tu veux une bière ?
-I have Rolling Rock or Amstel Light... -I killed someone today.
- Rolling Rock, Amstel Light... - J'ai tué quelqu'un aujourd'hui.
-Oh, my God. -It was this guy....
- Mon Dieu. - Il y avait ce mec...
Him and his woman were having a fight.
Il se battait avec sa femme.
They were obviously both high on something.
Ils étaient drogués.
He had a gun and....
Il avait une arme et...
I'm sure whatever it was, you did the right thing.
Je suis sûr que tu as bien agi.
He's dead, you fucking idiot!
Il est mort, espèce d'abruti !
I should have aimed at his arm or his leg.
J'aurais dû viser ses jambes.
I'm stupid.
Je suis un idiot.
I'm so fucking stupid.
Je suis un putain d'idiot.
I never killed someone before.
Je n'avais jamais tué personne.
I can't live with this.
Je ne le supporte pas.
I don't know how to help you.
Je ne sais pas comment t'aider.
Do you want to pray?
Tu veux prier ?
Maybe that would do something.
Ca peut t'aider.
David's not up yet?
David n'est pas levé ?
So where's Emily Previn?
Où est Emily Previn ?
She's in there.
Ici.
So she's not gonna have an open casket.
Cercueil fermé, donc.
-I couldn't do it. -Okay.
- J'ai pas pu faire autrement. - Très bien.
I was supposed to take the kids to dinner so Vanessa could have the night off.
Je devais emmener les gosses dîner pour libérer Vanessa ce soir.
But instead, I was here.
Au lieu de ça, je suis resté ici.
Until 9:00 last night.
Jusqu'à 21 heures.
Skin was fricking pouring off that woman's face!
La peau de cette femme dégoulinait de son visage !
I get all this shit from Vanessa, and I wasn't able to restore the poor lady!
Vanessa m'a pourri, et je n'ai même pas pu préparer cette pauvre femme !
Nobody could have.
Personne n'aurait pu.
But, here, you think you can do it?
Tu penses que tu pourrais le faire ?
Here's some tools.
Voilà les outils.
I want to watch you swim in that skin. Go ahead!
Va nager dans cette peau.
All I said was, "Okay. "
J'ai dit d'accord.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
I just wish I could've done her the way she wanted.
J'aurais voulu respecter ses volontés.
If it'll make you feel any better, I don't think there are even gonna be any mourners.
Personne ne viendra, si ça peut te consoler.
Thanks.
Merci.
Hello?
Allô ?
It's me.
C'est moi.
-I thought you were still here. -I had to get back home.
- Je croyais que tu étais encore là. - Je devais rentrer chez moi.
Are you okay?
Tu vas bien ?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Ca va.
Listen, what happened last night, that was wrong.
Je suis désolé pour hier soir.
I don't know why I went to you, but obviously I wasn't thinking right.
Je n'aurais pas dû venir vers toi, de toute évidence j'ai eu tort.
Obviously.
De toute évidence.
I'm in a relationship.
Je suis en couple.
I know that. I'm not an idiot.
Je sais, je ne suis pas idiot.
I just thought you and I could be friends...
Je pensais qu'on pourrait être amis,
but I was just kidding myself.
mais c'était des conneries.
Look, I don't think that you and I should see each other anymore.
Je ne crois pas qu'on devrait se revoir.
David?
David ?
Yeah, I'm here. Sure, whatever you want.
Fais comme tu veux.
I knew you would understand.
Je savais que tu comprendrais.
Goodbye.
Au revoir.
Thank you. That was intense.
Merci, c'était fort.
You're practically like jelly. You don't need this.
Tu es très détendue. Tu n'as pas besoin de ça.
Maybe not, but I love it.
Peut-être, mais j'adore.
You're gifted, you know that?
Tu es douée, tu sais ?
Hello?
Allô ?
Don't give me that bullshit, Allison. I want your ass there in half an hour.
Ne me sors pas ces conneries, Allison. Ramène ton cul dans une demi-heure.
Okay, fuck you. You are officially dead to me now.
Très bien, va te faire foutre. Tu n'existes plus pour moi.
Everything okay?
Tout va bien ?
I have a client at 2:15, and my watcher just cancelled.
J'ai un client à 2 h 15, et ma mateuse vient d'annuler.
Your watcher?
Ta mateuse ?
He likes to be watched by another girl while I do him.
Il aime qu'une nana le regarde pendant que je m'occupe de lui.
It's the easiest $100 in the world...
C'est 100 $ facilement gagnés,
and this asshole just blew me off for a runway audition.
et cette conne me pose un lapin pour un casting.
God, I hate models.
Je hais les mannequins.
Fuck.
Putain.
If you're sitting in the corner depressed, pick up.
Si tu es en pleine déprime, décroche !
Pick up.
Décroche.
All right, be depressed.
Très bien, déprime !
Listen, if you're in a jam....
Si tu es embêtée...
This isn't a science project, honey. This is business.
C'est pas une expérience de labo. C'est un boulot.
Please. You think I can't handle it?
Tu crois que je ne peux pas le faire ?
Like I said, it's pretty easy.
C'est facile.
Actually, it's like you're invisible. Just sitting and watching.
Il faut s'asseoir et regarder, comme une femme invisible.
I can do that.
Je peux faire ça.
I sit and watch all the time. In fact, that's mostly all I do.
C'est ce que je fais tout le temps.
I guess you've been in three-way situations before.
Tu l'as déjà fait à trois, je suppose.
-I mean, who hasn't? -Yeah.
- Comme tout le monde. - Oui.
Fuck.
Putain.
I've never seen you this angry before. It's terrific!
Je ne t'ai jamais vue autant en colère. Fantastique !
-No, my nephew made that. -Sorry.
- C'est mon neveu qui l'a fait. - Désolée.
Here, talk to me.
Parlez-moi.
This girl cheated on the SATs, and now she's gonna get away with it.
Cette fille a triché pour les exams, et elle va s'en sortir comme ça.
Okay, what's this girl's name?
Comment s'appelle-t-elle ?
When I realized what was going on, I just wanted to run and not take the test.
Quand j'ai compris, j'ai voulu m'enfuir sans les passer.
But I did. I took it, like an idiot. And what was the point?
Mais j'y suis allée, comme une idiote. Tout ça pour quoi ?
It's all just some stupid game.
C'est une sorte de jeu stupide.
I don't know what I want, but I don't want this.
Je ne sais pas ce que je veux, mais ce n'est pas ça.
And this is your excuse to bail?
C'est votre excuse pour gicler ?
Bail? What's that? Some hip lingo you think kids say?
Gicler ? Vous croyez que les jeunes parlent comme ça ?
-You are so lame sometimes. -Direct your anger at me, if you need to.
- Vous êtes si minable, parfois. - Défoulez-vous sur moi, allez-y.
By the way, you can fuck Parker McKenna, but if I were you, I'd wear a condom...
Vous pouvez baiser Parker McKenna, mais je vous conseille de mettre une capote,
because I'm sure she has hepatitis, at the very least.
parce qu'elle a sûrement l'hépatite, au minimum.
What are you talking about?
De quoi parlez-vous ?
If you're referring to the conversation I had with Parker, that's all it was.
On a parlé avec Parker, c'est tout.
A conversation.
Une conversation.
I have conversations with lots of young women. They approach me.
Je parle à beaucoup de jeunes femmes. Elles viennent vers moi.
Claire, I'm worried about you.
Claire, vous m'inquiétez.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
You're getting your life together, and it scares you.
Votre vie prend forme, et ça vous fait peur.
So you want to slip into the old habit of focusing on someone else's drama...
Vous voulez reprendre vos habitudes de vous concentrer sur les drames d'autrui
instead of concentrating on yourself. You need to stop doing that.
au lieu des vôtres. Il faut cesser ça.
You're right.
Vous avez raison.
And now is probably as good a time as any to talk about the sexual tension between us.
Il faudrait aborder le sujet de la tension sexuelle entre nous.
-What? -It exists.
- Quoi ? - Vous avez bien entendu.
It's a part of transference and counter-transference...
C'est en partie un transfert et un contre-transfert,
so we should acknowledge it's out there, and it'll never be acted upon...
on doit le reconnaître tous les deux, et surtout ne pas passer à l'acte,
because to do so would be irresponsible and destructive.
parce que ce serait irresponsable et destructeur.
Do you have anything that you would like to contribute?
Vous voulez ajouter quelque chose ?
No, I don't.
Non.
Okay.
Très bien.
I bet you I could glue this together if I tried hard.
Je dois pouvoir recoller ça.
I know people don't really glue things together anymore...
Ca ne se fait plus de nos jours,
but I could probably fix this.
mais je peux le faire.
You've reached the private line of David Fisher.
Vous êtes bien chez David Fisher.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Merci de laisser un message après le bip.
Hi, David. It's Ben. I'm calling to figure out what time's good for you on Saturday.
David, c'est Ben. Je me demandais quand tu serais libre samedi.
And I had a really good time last night, especially the making out part.
J'ai vraiment apprécié hier, surtout les baisers.
Okay. Bye.
Au revoir.
Yeah, honey.
Oui, chérie.
You know exactly how I like it.
Tu me fais ça très bien.
Come on. Move your tongue around it.
Allez, bouge un peu la langue.
Yeah.
Oui.
And I am telling you
Et je te dis
I'm not going
Que je ne m'en vais pas
I'm the best man you'll ever know
Jamais tu n'as rencontré de meilleur homme que moi
There's no way I could ever go
Je ne pourrais jamais partir
Nate, I love you!
Nate, je t'aime !
Now that I've heard this song five times in a row, I can honestly say I like it.
J'ai entendu cette chanson cinq fois, et je peux dire que je l'aime.
I'm here for the service.
Je viens pour la cérémonie.
Look around, nobody's here. There's not gonna be any service.
Il n'y a personne. Pas de cérémonie.
I couldn't even get a minister, and they get paid.
Je n'ai pas pu avoir de prêtre, et on les paye pour ça.
I've taken care of that. Father Jack is on his way here right now.
Je m'en suis occupée, le père Jack arrive tout de suite.
-Just give me 10 minutes. -For what?
- Donne-moi 10 minutes. - Pour quoi faire ?
-Federico? -Yes, Mrs. F?
- Federico ? - Oui, Mme F. ?
Could you come upstairs, please?
Vous pouvez monter, s'il vous plaît ?
Keith?
Keith ?
David, I need you for a few minutes.
David, j'ai besoin de toi un moment.
-Mom, I have a headache. -Too bad.
- Maman, j'ai mal à la tête. - Dommage.
-But I'm in the middle of a show. -Just do what I say!
- Je regarde une émission. - Tu fais ce que je dis !
And get out of those ragamuffin clothes.
Et mets autre chose que tes fringues de va-nu-pieds.
Why is this happening?
Qu'est-ce qu'il se passe ?
I don't know. Our structures probably need new fencing.
Je ne sais pas. Il devait manquer une barrière.
-And our roofs had bad shingles. -I had shingles once.
- Le toit doit être bouffé aux mites. - Comme quand j'ai eu des morpions.
She was supposed to have an open casket.
Il ne devait pas y avoir un cercueil ouvert ?
I did the best I could, okay?
J'ai fait de mon mieux, d'accord ?
I didn't see you down there helping me out.
Vous ne m'aidez pas des masses.
Leave it alone.
Laisse tomber.
We gather to mourn the passing of Emily Previn.
Nous sommes assemblés en mémoire d'Emily Previn.
I did not know Emily Previn.
Je ne la connaissais pas.
From what I gather, few, if any, people did.
Si j'ai bien compris, je ne suis pas le seul.
People might wonder what point there is in leading a life...
On peut se demander pourquoi vivre une vie
where you don't touch any other lives.
isolée des autres.
But it would be arrogant of us to assume that.
Ce serait arrogant de notre part.
Every life is a contribution. We just may not see how.
Chaque vie apporte quelque chose. Même si nous ne le voyons pas.
I'm glad to encounter Emily Previn, even if it is in death.
Je suis heureux de la rencontrer, même dans la mort.
Everyone comes into our life for a reason...
Chaque vie a une raison d'être,
and it is our responsibility to learn what they have to teach us.
et il nous incombe d'en tirer un enseignement.
Now, in accordance with Emily's wishes...
Selon les volontés d'Emily,
I will read from the Book of Matthew, Chapter 11.
je vais lire l'évangile selon Saint Mathieu, chapitre 11.
Strange, but somehow I feel like Emily won.
C'était comme si Emily avait gagné.
She remains a fucking question mark right up to the bitter end.
La question est restée sans réponse jusqu'au bout.
Basically all I know about her is that she kept Wheat Thins in her refrigerator.
Tout ce qu'on sait d'elle, c'est qu'elle gardait ses biscuits au frigo.
That's something.
C'est déjà pas mal.
So, tell your mother I have to get back to work.
Dis à ta mère que je dois retourner au travail.
Unlike some people.
Pas comme certains.
I'm sorry, Federico, but I have a headache. Am I not allowed to have a headache?
Désolé, Federico, mais j'ai une migraine. J'ai le droit, non ?
-It's so good to see you. -Hello, Father.
- Je suis heureux de vous voir. - Mon père.
How is everything at St. Stephen's?
Comment vont les choses à St. Stephen ?
It's okay.
Ca va.
Apropos of what I said earlier, I wanted to thank you, David.
Je voulais vous remercier, David.
I'm really glad you came into my life.
Je suis heureux de vous connaître.
You will never know how much you taught me about myself.
Vous ne saurez jamais ce que j'ai appris sur moi grâce à vous.
Really? How so?
Vraiment ? Comment ?
Another time, maybe.
Une autre fois, peut-être.
-You look a little sad. -I have a headache.
- Vous avez l'air triste. - J'ai mal à la tête.
Well, God bless.
Soyez béni.
David, come over here. There's something I want to say to the three of you.
David, tu viens ? Je veux vous parler, à tous les trois.
Oh, Lord, our gutters are clogged. I think we need to see about removing the leaves.
Seigneur, nos gouttières sont bouchées, il faut enlever les feuilles.
That's very funny, Claire.
Très drôle, Claire.
I know you think The Plan is ridiculous.
Je sais, vous pensez que Le Plan est ridicule.
-No, we don't. -We just think it's weird.
- Non. - On pense que c'est bizarre.
Did any one of you wonder why I felt the need to change the structure of my life?
Savez-vous pourquoi je désire changer la structure de ma vie ?
Did you even care?
Vous vous en fichez ?
At first I didn't understand why I was so upset about Emily Previn.
Je n'ai pas tout de suite compris pourquoi Emily Previn me touchait tant.
Then it hit me. I don't want to turn into her.
Puis j'ai compris. Je ne veux pas finir comme elle.
Life is hard enough without not having people to help you.
La vie est dure, mais sans personne pour vous aider...
-But, Mom, you have us. -I do not.
- Mais maman, on est là. - Non.
Nate, you've been walking around like a zombie for months.
Nate, tu es comme un zombie depuis des mois.
You're lying in bed during the day, God knows why.
Tu restes allongé toute la journée.
I have a headache.
J'ai mal à la tête.
Claire, I can't even look in your direction...
Claire, je ne peux pas te regarder,
without you acting like it's some incredible imposition.
sans que tu réagisses comme si j'étais le Grand Inquisiteur.
All I want is for us not to be strangers. I want some intimacy.
Je ne veux pas que nous soyons des étrangers les uns pour les autres.
Give me intimacy.
Je veux qu'on soit proches.
Won't any of you have intimacy with me?
Qui peut se rapprocher de moi ?
Okay, I guess I have my answer.
J'ai la réponse à ma question.
Mom, wait.
Maman, attends.
I just think that intimacy should happen a little more organically than this.
Se rapprocher, ça doit être plus spontané que ça.
Fine. Then I'll simply wait for it like I have been.
Très bien. J'attendrai, comme d'habitude.
I just pray that it happens before I end up like Emily Previn.
Je prie que ça arrive avant de finir comme elle.
Now, if you'll please excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
When I saw you typing at your computer, you had the strangest expression.
Quand je t'ai vue à l'ordinateur, tu avais une expression étrange.
I was writing. It's called flow.
J'écrivais, j'étais dans mon truc.
You know all about flow, don't you?
Tu connais ça, non ?
Let me ask you a question.
Je peux te poser une question ?
Do you think you and I have as much intimacy as you want?
Tu trouves qu'on est assez proches ?
I don't have as much of anything as I want.
Je n'ai jamais assez de rien.
That's not really much of an answer.
Ce n'est pas vraiment une réponse.
It wasn't really much of a question.
Ce n'était pas vraiment une question.
Did you remember to lock the door?
Tu as bien fermé la porte ?
Yes, I did, for the second time. You've been acting strange tonight.
Oui, ça fait deux fois que je te le dis. Tu es bizarre, ce soir.
-What do you mean? -Well, you've been all jumpy.
- Que veux-tu dire ? - Tu es nerveuse.
Oh, God.
Mon Dieu.
Okay, something has been on my mind.
D'accord, il y a quelque chose qui me turlupine.
Nate Fisher...
Nate Fisher,
would you be my wife?
veux-tu être ma femme ?
My God, this isn't what I was expecting.
Je ne m'attendais pas à ça.
-Is that a no? -No, of course not.
- C'est non ? - Bien sûr que non.
It is kind of an ugly ring. It's got these Greek letters on it.
Il est affreux, cet anneau, il y a des lettres en grec dessus.
Delta Phi Delta. It's my grandfather's fraternity ring.
Delta Phi Delta. C'était l'anneau de fraternité de mon grand-père.
I found it when I was cleaning up...
Je l'ai trouvé en rangeant,
and that's when I got the idea...
c'est comme ça que j'ai eu l'idée
to propose to you.
de te demander en mariage.
So why today?
Pourquoi aujourd'hui ?
I don't know.
Je ne sais pas.
I just started thinking...
Je pensais :
I don't know what I'd do if I ever lost you.
et si je le perdais, qu'est-ce que je ferais sans lui ?
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
Je ne vais nulle part.
Promise?
Promis ?
Of course I'll marry you. I love you. Absolutely.
Je t'épouserai. Je t'aime.
I love you. Yeah, let's get married!
Je t'aime. Oui, marions-nous !
Yes! Let's get married!
Oui, marions-nous !
Come on!
Allez !
I love you, too.
Je t'aime aussi.